

**Pedro** Ciancaglini Associate Director Senior Manager

EY Client Technology - Global

Moving to Spain - Madrid on April 5, 2024

# Contact Information Mobile: +5491141693129

Use this AI tool I developed to analyze if this profile matches with your Job Description: Click Here

#### Email:

pedrociancaglini@gmail.com

#### LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/pedr ociancaglini/

## Latest Products

[1] EY Fabric - Cloud Layer Products [2] EY Fabric - Intelligence Layer Products [3] EYQ Platform [4] EY.ai

#### **Industry lines**

- Technology
- Energy Sector (out of EY)

## Education & Languages

- Associate degree in Mechanics
- Hult Executive MBA (2023)

#### Certification(s)

- Certified Scrum Master (2019)
- Certified SAFe Scrum Master (22)
- Advance Certified Scrum Master (2022)

## **Hobbies**

- Spending Time with Family and Friends
- Technology

# Background

- Pedro is a Delivery Director in the Intelligence Program for EY Fabric Platform
- ► Pedro joined EY in 2021 as Assistant Director 1 63-1 and is based at GDS Argentina in Buenos Aires. 2 year later, Pedro was promoted to Associate Director 1, 62, 1.

He has 20 years of experience in the technology industry with 10 years spent on service delivery operations serving to 10k users distributed in Latin America. In the last nine years, he served as infrastructure manager, leading complex infrastructure projects with the migration of an on-premises datacentre with a portfolio of services to Microsoft Office 365 cloud.

In 2021, Pedro shifted his career to the software industry. Pedro was the Scrum Master in a key product in EY Fabric, EY Cloud Risk View. Workforce: 50 developers, Delivering: 400 features per year, Delivering Rate: 90%.

In July 2022, he was appointed as Release Train Engineer for Zero Trust and Commercial Agile Release Trains in the Cloud Program within EY Fabric. He was managing 11 Scrum Masters, and around 250 developers. During this period, Pedro created a set of analytics tools using AI, BI, and RPA to monitor the complex delivery which was later expanded to EY Fabric. He also co-created a taskforce to standardize the delivery practice across EY Fabric

In July 2023, he was appointed as Layer Delivery Leader for the Intelligence Layer, the Al program within EY Fabric. With his previous experience in Generative AI (Since 2020) and Machine Learning (Since 2017), Business Intelligence (Since 2013), he contributed to sophisticate and systematize any operation.

#### Skills

- Artificial intelligence, Data Science and Business Intelligence: Creating Data-driven culture.
- Power Platform Suite: Assisting in the creation of full stack solutions to operate in a more efficient way using Power Automate, PowerApps, PowerBl and SharePoint.
- Soft skills: Negotiation (Harvard Style using BATNA), Communication, Critical thinking, System Thinking.
- Special Projects: Delivery Reports, Agile Copilot (GenAl GPT Type Assistant),
   Shadowing Machine (Agile School for new comers)
- Project Management Frameworks: Project Management, Scrum, Scaled Agile.

## Professional Experience (Latest Relevant)

- Layer Delivery Director EY CT Jul 2023 Present: Pedro is assisting the EY Fabric Intelligence Layer as Delivery Leader and Solution Train Engineer, coaching Layer Leaders, and Train Leaders in the Scrum Practice, aligning Layer to EY Fabric Standards, adjusting the delivery strategy to EY Fabric goals and priorities. Pedro is also leading the engineering initiatives for the Delivery Office and Alignment Teams, leading the development of tools to cascade standards to all layers in EY Fabric.
- ▶ Release Train Engineer EY CT Jul 2022 Jun 2023: Pedro assisted EY Fabric Cloud Layer in the Zero Trust and Commercial Trains as Release Train Engineer, advising the scrum teams in the SAFe scrum methodology, helping products to achieve higher delivery ratios, with the motto: "Delivering better and faster".
- Scrum Master EY CT Jul 2021 to Jul 2022: Pedro served as scrum master to the product and the scrum teams (four), facilitating the scrum events, assisting the product team with the Product Incremental (PI) Planning, and advising them with the best SAFe Scrum practices to achieve their PI goals. Turned PI completion ratio from 80% to 95%, introducing the Release process, creating a regular release cadence.
- ▶ Data and Digital Officer ENGIE Jul 2019 to Jun 2021: He served the company as subject matter resource in the data science and Internet of things fields, advising the company regional office and subsidiaries with the data transformation strategy, helping to adopt data technology and assist in the implementation of the first four key data-driven processes and its transformation journey to a data-driven organization. Also Acting as Product Manager, Product Owner and Scrum Master for various Digital Products.
- ► Technology Manager ENGIE Oct 2014 to Jul 2019: He served the company's regional office and subsidiaries in the Latin American Region assisting in the migration of an on-premises datacenter to the Microsoft Office 365 cloud, assisting with the maintenance of the regional infrastructure.